James Hart

hjhart+resume@gmail.com (425) 835-2366 http://hjhart.com

Having worked remotely from Seattle with my coworkers in San Francisco for four years, I'm looking for a remote position on a team where I can continue to grow as an engineer as well as help steer the engineering team and product. I consider myself a full-stack engineer favoring the back-end and operations. I have eight years of experience of writing web applications with Ruby on Rails. I have deployed and configured all pieces of infrastructure necessary to run a scalable server-side application, including nginx, haproxy, postgresql, memcached, redis, solr, elasticsearch. I have extensive front-end work with Javascript, HTML, and CSS with some of the older frameworks. I am a voracious learner and enjoy working with like-minded people.

GitHub hjhart LinkedIn hjameshart

SKILLS

RUBY	Rails, Capistrano, Sidekiq, RSpec, Sinatra
OPERATIONS	Docker, Chef, Ansible, Bash, Nginx, Redis
DATA STORES / SEARCH	PostgreSQL, Redis, Solr, Memcached, ElasticSearch, MySQL
FRONT-END	Jasmine, Backbone, jQuery, PhoneGap, Foundation, Bootstrap, Sass, HTML
TOOLING	Git, Vim, RubyMine, Pivotal Tracker, Travis Cl, Circle Cl, Jenkins

EXPERIENCE

Wanelo

Director of Engineering Jul 2013 - Apr 2018

At Wanelo, I led the engineering team for numerous years in both application development and platform operations. Under the direction of the CEO and the product team, I advised product owners how we should engineer our numerous products. I led the team that built and maintained our marketplace for selling products on Shopify. During our growth period, I helped build scalable solutions to handle user growth by sharding postgresql for our user saves. When our user base was declining, I helped advise the company to downgrade our servers and other third-party services to go from \$115k to \$60k in monthly operating costs.

RPX

Senior Software Engineer Oct 2010 - Jul 2013

Became the lead engineer on our client-facing ruby on rails application. Worked over at Pivotal Labs for six months working using Ruby on Rails and learning agile methods and TDD. Lead the front-end development

of a single-page backbone application. Built a gem to integrate multiple of our ruby applications onto the same database. Worked on several "hackathon" projects to help improve the workflow of other teams within the company. Built and maintained multiple ruby on rails applications and one Backbone.js application. Built an API to interface between postgres stored procedures and a rails application.

Lean Startup Productions

Freelance Software Engineer Aug 2013 - Dec 2014

Worked closely with clients to enhance Eric Ries' Conference's website for two years. Test drove new conference software that matched attendees to their preferred mentors test-driven in pure ruby. Helped operate said software for two conferences (Lean Startup Conference 2014, QuickBooks Connect 2014). Built and maintained entrepeneurial editorial site called "The How."

Tara Mohr

Freelance Software Engineer Oct 2013 - May 2014

Built and maintained members' only wordpress website. Coordinated with third-party software developers to improve their wordpress plugin (WooCommerce).

EggWich iPhone App

Creator and Developer Oct 2010 - Jul 2013

EggWich is an iPhone application highlighting reviews and photos of egg sandwiches and breakfast burritos in San Francisco. The app was test-driven using Jasmine. I used the Enyo.js framework (previously Palm WebOS) to generate views and handle all user events. Runs on iOS using Phonegap.

WebKey LLC

Web Developer May 2008 - Sep 2010

The owner and I worked closely with one another to deliver our clients with web design and development. I developed secure and usable web forms with PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Experience with customer service by providing clients help for their questions, performing user interviews, and recommending solutions to any bugs or errors they might have found. Clients include: Fremont Brewing Company, Washington Green Roads, Richard Conlin (Seattle City Council), Washington Green Schools, and many more.

hjhart.com

Freelance Web Design and Development Aug 2006 - Sep 2010

I've used numerous different methods of development: from using open-source content management systems, to developing everything from scratch. Designing was always done in-house using Photoshop. Development occurs on a PHP/MySQL platform, with the use of standards-compliant HTML and CSS with

JavaScript. With these projects, building my skill set is very important as is communicating with the client exactly what they require. Clients include: Damon Barnett, Night Owl Lounge, Carso's Pasta, Saga Beverages, WoofSites, PitchSmarter, Bainbridge Island Yacht Club, and many more.

VOLUNTEERING

Basset Hound Rescue of Southern California

Web Developer Jan 2014 - Jun 2015

Basset Hound Rescue of Southern California is a 501(c)3 non-profit organization offering sanctuary, healing and forever families to distressed, abandoned, injured or homeless hounds.

Golden Gate Ruby Conference

Web Developer May 2013 - Sep 2013

GoGaRuCo was a great single-track conference in San Francisco that ran for six years. I approached the cohost of the conference to help build the website. used the middleman gem to produce static HTML, CSS3 and JavaScript hosted on github pages. We used the Foundation framework and its css and javascript to build a responsive website across browsers and devices.

EDUCATION

University of Washington

Sep 2005 - Jun 2010 Bachelor of Science - Informatics

University of Washington

Sep 2005 - Jun 2010 Bachelor of Science - Mathematics